# Ali Raza

Lahore, 54590 Punjab, Pakistan +92 305 7381431 Github: <u>alirazamumtaz</u>
LinkedIn: <u>alirazamumtaz</u>
Webiste: <u>alirazamumtaz.github.io</u>
Email: elirazamumtaz@gmail.com

#### Research Interests

My research interests lie in the intersection of computer security and low-level systems. I am interested in the security vulnerabilities posed by systems, and how they can be exploited. For now, I am working on my FYP thesis that is about reproducing CVE-2019-2215 which is the Use After Free vulnerability in Android Kernel's Binder IPC subsystem.

#### Education

## **PUCIT** - University of the Punjab

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

• Expected graduation: July 2023

• GPA: 3.65/4.0

#### Punjab Group of Colleges, Okara Campus

**Intermediate of Computer Science with Physics** 

• Graduated with 3rd position in BISE Sahiwal.

September, 2019 – Present

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

2017 - 2019

Okara, Punjab, Pakistan

## Research Experience

#### Vulnerability Research and Exploit Development for Android Kernel

July, 2022 - Present

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

- Supervisor: Dr. Muhammad Arif Butt
- · Formulated the idea and initiated the research project
- Worked on problems related to memory errors in binaries
- Worked on reversing binaries using IDA Freeware
- Worked on chroot jailbreak
- · Working on analysing Linux kernel

## Professional Experience

#### Malware Researcher

March, 2023 – Present

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

Ebryx (Pvt.) Ltd.

Working on Kernel Vulnerability Research and Exploitation

- Linux Kernel Auditing
- Tools: IDA Pro, Ghidra, GDB, OEMU, etc.

## Teaching Assistant (Operating Systems)

October, 2022 – February, 2023

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

Designed material and coursework for the newly introduced lab component of the subject

- Designed exam papers for the lab
- Assisted students in the lab + other TA responsibilities

#### **Programming Tutor**

April, 2022 - Present

Fiverr.com

Freelance on Fiverr

- Teaching low level programming concepts in C
- Teaching object oriented programming in C++

Programming Languages: C, Python, Java, C#, x86-64 Assembly

Security: Binary Exploitation, Reverse Engineering

Tools: IDA, GDB, GNU/Make

OS: MacOS, Linux

## **Projects**

Unix Shell C, Makefile

https://github.com/alirazamumtaz/unix-shell

An effort to write the \*nix based shell to gain understanding of how shell works and how OS
creates and handles processes and allows processes to communicate with each other through it's
IPC interface

Exploits Scripts Python, x86 Assembly

https://github.com/alirazamumtaz/exploit-development

• Basic scripts that I have written to solve some exploitation challenges

Hack Assembler C++

https://github.com/alirazamumtaz/hack-assembler

• A 16-bit machine language assembler for the 16-bit Hack Assembly Language. This was done as part of building a complete 16-bit computer during the Computer Organization Assembly Language Course

## Courses & MOOCs

## Computer Systems Security: pwn.college

- Shellcode Injection
- Sandboxing
- Reverse Engineering
- Memory Errors
- Race Conditions
- Kernel Security
- Program Exploitation

### Extracurriculars & Volunteering

# Club Leader

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

2021 – 2022 & 2022 – Present

Google Developer Student Clubs

- Faculty Contact: Assist. Prof. Abdul Mateen
- Organized tech workshops and seminars
- E.g. CodeFest, Hacktoberfest, etc

## **Event Organiser**

**Event Management Society** 

- Organized inter-college events
- E.g. Job Fair, Trips, etc

## PUCIT - University of the Punjab 2020 - 2021 & 2022 - Present

#### Awards & Honors

Board Topper 2019

Intermediate - BISE Sahiwal
• https://pgc.edu/our-achievers/

Sahiwal, Pakistan

 Awarded with a brass medal and a cash prize by the Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education, Sahiwal